[{"id": "5a25f2186682715b82711ce7", "question": "Feijoada, the national dish of Brazil, originates from which country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa59773838c5c8a417f27", "question": "Ambergris is a waxy substance that originates as a secretion from what animal?", "answer": "Sperm whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd5d2e347d002c297e4b8", "question": "The novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\" is the second book in which pentalogy?", "answer": "Leatherstocking Tales", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e966c7ccba3ffe45786ed", "question": "In which country would you find the Tokaj wine region?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b175", "question": "What year was the state of California ceded to the US from Mexico?", "answer": "1848", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddf166ce05a3942286dae", "question": "In which year was Tiger Woods named the PGA Tour Rookie of the Year?", "answer": "1996", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc65", "question": "What do collectors call the first complete Hot Wheels line-up of cars?", "answer": "Sweet 16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b82c364247bf200fb87c", "question": "For which game was the Steam Workshop service created to allow players to share modifications?", "answer": "Team Fortress 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa39bfc73aa70ea0b70adb", "question": "In which country did the Mambo dance originate?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e1", "question": "What color is the bottom strip of Egypt's flag?", "answer": "Black", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abaa", "question": "What is the state capital of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f1", "question": "What happens when you roll three consecutive doubles in a game of Monopoly?", "answer": "You go to jail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a948", "question": "What city is the eastern terminus of the Trans-Siberian Railway?", "answer": "Vladivostok", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d2", "question": "Nick Carter was a member of which boy band?", "answer": "Backstreet Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a6", "question": "In what country was the last original Volkswagen Beetle produced, in July 2003?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebd", "question": "John Carpenter's \"Assault on Precinct 13\" is an homage to what classic Howard Hawks western?", "answer": "Rio Bravo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e0f506d333868d34d723", "question": "What was the name given to the laws aimed at enforcing segregation in public places in the United States?", "answer": "Jim Crow Laws", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb10765ff7d326b622a65", "question": "Who sang \"No More Heroes\" in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Stranglers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12e58e39efa6330e0fed2", "question": "Which US state has the most lighthouses?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b8", "question": "In the children's toe-counting rhyme, what did the third little piggy have?", "answer": "Roast Beef", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323211bf195a31e15d738c", "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which Central American country?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e14cfe83fe1f2a824b93", "question": "What best describes Germany\u2019s standard invasion strategy at the beginning of World War II?", "answer": "Attack with a combination of speed and overwhelming force (blitzkrieg)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5bab6ce05a3942286e18", "question": "What was the name of Bob Ross' TV show?", "answer": "\"The Joy of Painting\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd3", "question": "What was the Boulder Dam renamed to in 1947?", "answer": "Hoover Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7f", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Dragon Seed\"?", "answer": "Pearl S. Buck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950b", "question": "Who plays the role of Martin Riggs in the Lethal Weapon movie series?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b779", "question": "How many holes are there in a standard Ritz cracker?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef2", "question": "In which English city would you find The Christmas Steps?", "answer": "Bristol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9f", "question": "What candy bar was named for a beloved horse of the Mars family?", "answer": "Snickers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c545", "question": "In which part of the body are your metatarsals located?", "answer": "Foot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e5", "question": "Who directed the film \"Serpico\"?", "answer": "Sidney Lumet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab6", "question": "What is the more common name for Cerumen?", "answer": "Earwax", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928b", "question": "\"Highlander\" tells the story of which immortal swords-man?", "answer": "Connor MacLeod", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f164c3ff9b80650dbe7f92e", "question": "How many years was Captain America frozen for in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?", "answer": "66", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c056", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Israel?", "answer": "Hoopoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dfd", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Eros?", "answer": "Cupid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a639", "question": "What animal is depicted on the flag of California?", "answer": "Grizzly Bear", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb11", "question": "What early arcade game used a trackball rather than a joystick?", "answer": "Missile Command", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8df7ec223966ae8f885a", "question": "What actor plays M. Gustave in the movie \"The Grand Budapest Hotel\"?", "answer": "Ralph Fiennes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9eb", "question": "Who is considered to be the creator of the \"Gran Turismo\" game series?", "answer": "Kazunori Yamauchi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008f8bcf842fa4c4ba96bd", "question": "Who is the Roman Patron Saint of hangovers?", "answer": "Saint Bibiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ce", "question": "Which is the largest of the Caribbean islands?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a8", "question": "What two types of ashes are jointly called coal ash?", "answer": "Fly Ash and Bottom Ash", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49c", "question": "Which country was selected as a host of the 1916 Olympic Games, but didn't actually host them?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a2", "question": "Who was the first man to return safely from space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b579", "question": "What is an airline's home base called?", "answer": "Hub", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062c5ac9d816e292245c2b", "question": "What element was removed from Leonardo da Vinci's The Last Supper by careless workers?", "answer": "While installing a doorway in the wall that holds\u00a0\"The Last Supper\", builders cut into the mural, lopping off\u00a0Jesus' feet.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde5223c6c6b019850c9a95", "question": "Britain annexed Hong Kong as a result of which war?", "answer": "The Opium War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990f8a6fa5fdd6dd25324ef", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f1671af7c52aae91cc07b5", "question": "What was the codename of the Allied invasion of French North Africa in 1942?", "answer": "Operation Torch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea83daff048f679a45ac2c", "question": "In what constellation can the North Star be found?", "answer": "Ursa Minor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd72fe347d002c297e4bf", "question": "Which US state gets the most rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbe7b6ce05a3942286ef1", "question": "Who first recorded the song \"Last Christmas\"?", "answer": "Wham!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa6a173838c5c8a417f30", "question": "How many teeth does an aardvark have?", "answer": "None", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b32324fbf195a31e15d738f", "question": "Which novel did George Eliot publish in 1876?", "answer": "Daniel Deronda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6012195a63c99d48cd169af8", "question": "How many bricks were used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "10 million", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e6", "question": "What are the two main ingredients of mayonnaise?", "answer": "Oil and egg yolk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba2f7874c93a3298b2137", "question": "A Villanelle is a type of what?", "answer": "Poem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0b", "question": "The TV series \"NCIS\" was a spin-off from what other series?", "answer": "JAG", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339813", "question": "The song \"Disco Inferno\" appeared on the soundtrack to what 1970s movie?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aabf", "question": "Which Canadian island is named after the father of Queen Victoria?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d47f2b42d4a3561a9efa", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", who did Katchoo visit when she disappeared in Canada for 2 months?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bdc", "question": "Lenny Kravtiz is the son of what popular sitcom actress?", "answer": "Roxie Roker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339146", "question": "Who created the character Pinocchio?", "answer": "Carlo Collodi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aca", "question": "The story of Cinderella was written by which French author?", "answer": "Charles Perrault", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1d", "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71b", "question": "What do South Africans decorate at Christmas time with cotton, wool and tinsel?", "answer": "Their windows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c08", "question": "What year was model Anna Nicole Smith born?", "answer": "1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af20", "question": "What name is given to William the conqueror's survey of England in 1086?", "answer": "The Domesday Book", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f3e73af848b908361b869", "question": "What fruit was originally called the \"Chinese Gooseberry\"?", "answer": "Kiwi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba96", "question": "The pasta shape called \"farfalle\" gets its name from the Italian word for what insect?", "answer": "Butterfly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339201", "question": "In what movie does Redfoot flick his cigarette into the face of McManus?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ca", "question": "What David Guterson novel was made into a 1999 motion picture?", "answer": "Snow Falling on Cedars", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abe", "question": "What was Drew Barrymore's character\u2019s name in \"E.T.: The Extra-Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Gertie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e8fdb24f84e0b9f9ffc7", "question": "What does the name Botswana mean?", "answer": "Land of the Tswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339647", "question": "In which film did Michael Douglas play the part of Gordon Gekko?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995b", "question": "Robert Englund played the main villain in what series of horror films?", "answer": "A Nightmare on Elm Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a0", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the sun?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c671", "question": "What species of poisonous spider has an hourglass pattern on its abdomen?", "answer": "Black Widow Spider", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad27", "question": "What Undersecretary of the United Nations became the first African-American to win the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Ralph Bunche", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ad", "question": "What does the \"PJ\" stand for in the name PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a3", "question": "What does the Roman numeral C represent?", "answer": "100", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7e", "question": "Baku is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Azerbaijan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa03", "question": "What capital city translates as Capital City in the native tongue?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25ca1b63e5727cf5a4861", "question": "In which city was Tupac Shakur shot dead?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aa1c01dd7bf43be5e757", "question": "What is the Hebrew term for \"commandment\"?", "answer": "Mitzvah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb68d65ff7d326b622a97", "question": "The 1980s \"High Society\" was a musical remake of which 1930s play?", "answer": "The Philadelphia Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae80", "question": "What company printed its first mail-order catalog in 1887?", "answer": "Sears Roebuck and Co.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cafb877e98cb97778a10", "question": "What is the highest navigable body of water in the world?", "answer": "Lake Titicaca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939c", "question": "Who plays the role of Captain John Miller in the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\"?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa5526ce05a3942286ebd", "question": "Which meal made the flight crew and some of the passengers ill in the comedy \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe606ce05a3942286eee", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Everybody Wants to Rule the World\"?", "answer": "Tears For Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ce72877e98cb97778a42", "question": "Which place is dubbed as \"The Salad Bowl of the Philippines\"?", "answer": "Benguet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121b4f63c99d48cd169b0d", "question": "\"Astrolatry\" is the worship of what as deities?", "answer": "Celestial bodies -- People who practice astrolatry consider the sun, moon, stars and other celestial bodies as gods.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95aeff55722f97b22684d7", "question": "In the \"Star Wars\" franchise, how many languages is C-3PO fluent in?", "answer": "Over six million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe4", "question": "What do the four letters stand for in the name of the US government agency FEMA?", "answer": "Federal Emergency Management Agency", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7f", "question": "Does \"verbatim\" mean?", "answer": "In the same words", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a203", "question": "What was Lucille Ball's Broadway stage name?", "answer": "Diane Belmont and Dianne Belmont", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d05f81a1c922dd1ac64a7", "question": "Vatican City and what other country have square flags?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea788fff048f679a45abdb", "question": "What is a \"Haricot Vert\"?", "answer": "A tender string bean", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133986a", "question": "In Disney's \"Cinderella\", what is the cats name?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339300", "question": "What song does Ferris Bueller sing from the float in the Chicago parade?", "answer": "Twist and Shout", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdf", "question": "What instrument did Lionel Hampton introduce to jazz in 1930?", "answer": "The vibraphone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c920", "question": "The Amazon river dolphins are what colour?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96c7023c87fd04dd15e25", "question": "What instrument did Paul McCartney primarily play as a member of the Beatles?", "answer": "Bass", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6f", "question": "Which empire was the first empire in history?", "answer": "The Akkadians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bde", "question": "Which fictional criminal has a sidekick called Bunny?", "answer": "Raffles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb5d285dad637d903c8822", "question": "What is Valentine's Day called in Brazil?", "answer": "Dia dos Namorados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339757", "question": "Who wrote My Girl, the hit song performed by the Temptations?", "answer": "Smokey Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a696", "question": "Which country has the longest coastline?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab7", "question": "Who wrote, Spirit of the Season in 1993?", "answer": "Heather Graham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b6", "question": "How many sides does a trapezoid have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f2", "question": "What US state has been governed by Evan Mecham and Bruce Babbitt?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339901", "question": "What was Herbie the Lovebug's racing number?", "answer": "53", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5a", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the concertmaster?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133979f", "question": "Who played bad girl Sammy Jo in \"Dynasty\", then bad girl Amanda in \"Melrose Place\"?", "answer": "Heather Locklear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c727", "question": "What element\u2019s chemical symbol is the letter \"I\"?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3d", "question": "Which is the only one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World still standing?", "answer": "The Great Pyramid of Khufu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a424", "question": "In what state would you find the supposed UFO site named \"Area 51\"?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f92", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Alfie\"?", "answer": "Vivien Merchant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d80", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Matthew Harrison Brady in the novel \"Inherit the Wind\"?", "answer": "William Jennings Bryan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc1", "question": "For what college did Dan Marino play football?", "answer": "University of Pittsburgh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9e", "question": "In the nursery rhyme \"Ladybird, Ladybird\", why is the bug told to \"fly away home\"?", "answer": "Her house is on fire and her children are gone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a415", "question": "What US city is home to the annual \"All-American Soap Box Derby\"?", "answer": "Akron, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba71", "question": "Founded in 1924, what department store\u2019s name includes the street of its original New York City address?", "answer": "Saks Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071cdd3745b36be73039d1", "question": "Who worked as the lead Soviet rocket engineer during the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union?", "answer": "Sergei Korolev", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b008", "question": "What city in Idaho was the first in the world to use electricity generated by nuclear power?", "answer": "Arco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc9", "question": "What TV persona made Cassandra Peterson a star?", "answer": "Elvira", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f44", "question": "\"Pee-Wee's Big Adventure\" is to recover what beloved stolen item?", "answer": "His bike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bd5afb6c85e9e634ff67", "question": "What is the atomic number of Antimony?", "answer": "51", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339191", "question": "What is tattooed on Popeye's arm?", "answer": "An anchor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339112", "question": "Who wrote the 1897 novel \"The Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f4a", "question": "What long-running soap opera dropped the \"The\" in its title in 1975?", "answer": "Guiding Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e50", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Black Caesar\"?", "answer": "Fred Williamson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66246a5bfecdd737e0843", "question": "Who was the oldest Chief Justice appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court?", "answer": "Harlan Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b8", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Pisces\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339157", "question": "Which TV show features a character nicknamed \"Sweet Dee\"?", "answer": "It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa7", "question": "What Saturday Evening Post artist was known for his whimsical pictures of Santa Claus?", "answer": "Norman Rockwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8afb901dd7bf43be5e78a", "question": "What is the term for a word that is spelled the same forwards and backwards?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e2", "question": "In which Chinese city is the Terracotta Army?", "answer": "Xian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2f", "question": "Which ocean is the region of Melanesia located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76d", "question": "What type of skin cancer starts in the pigment cells, often after too much sun exposure?", "answer": "Melanoma", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f78efe83fe1f2a824c22", "question": "When was the fast food chain, Mcdonalds, founded?", "answer": "Mcdonald's was founded on April 15th, 1955 in Des Plaines, Illinois.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c524", "question": "Where in your body would you find your hippocampus?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948b", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Leaving Las Vegas\"?", "answer": "Mike Figgis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b028", "question": "The major battle of what city was fought on January 8, 1815?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b34ce662d71a53650fdd", "question": "Who wrote the opening line, \"All children, except one, grow up\"?", "answer": "J.M. Barrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8b", "question": "What rock musician is known as \"The Motor City Madman\"?", "answer": "Ted Nugent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5f", "question": "In what Missouri town did Mark Twain grow up?", "answer": "Hannibal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a376", "question": "What is the capital of Sweden?", "answer": "Stockholm", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e3f35d5cb9e8bda6821363", "question": "What ancient city did Swiss explorer Johann Ludwig Burckhardt introduce to the Western world in 1812?", "answer": "Petra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2c", "question": "The title for the novel \"A Brave New World\" was derived from which Shakespearean play?", "answer": "The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339873", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", who is the companion of The Walrus?", "answer": "A Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55b", "question": "The city of New Orleans is located in which state?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339861", "question": "In Disney's \"Snow White\", what kind of animal heart does the Huntsman give to the Queen in place of Snow White's?", "answer": "A Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aafa", "question": "Which country borders Chad to the north?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029f48cad1ec93f27df75e", "question": "Which empire gave the world the Pilsner?", "answer": "The Austrian Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a805", "question": "What is the name of the Canadian territory that shares a land border with Alaska?", "answer": "Yukon Territory", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54e", "question": "What digit does not exist in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b683", "question": "What is dentophobia a common fear of?", "answer": "Dentists", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aafc", "question": "What bay does the Ganges River flow into?", "answer": "Bay of Bengal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c038", "question": "What is the fear of dependence on others known as?", "answer": "Soteriophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7359deec85e375820b24e", "question": "Who said, \"Courage is what it takes to stand up and speak, it\u2019s also what it takes to sit down and listen.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cf7abb53d1af658864f4", "question": "In the film \"Home Alone 2\", what city was the McCallister family planning on vacationing in?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9a", "question": "What kind of lunch is the common British pub meal of a piece of Cheddar, crusty bread, and a pickle?", "answer": "Ploughman's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe768e8eec85e375820b2a9", "question": "What is the record snowfall in Phoenix, Arizona?", "answer": "One inch", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ec", "question": "In what decade was the Social Security Act signed into law?", "answer": "1930's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339129", "question": "What year did Camille Saint-Saens' opera \"Samson and Delilah\" debut?", "answer": "1877", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e2a7fe83fe1f2a824ba1", "question": "What Japanese action created tension with the United States?", "answer": "Japan's seizure of territory in China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed6", "question": "Who fights crime alongside a German shepherd named Ace?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a5", "question": "The character Lieutenant Pinkerton appears in what opera?", "answer": "Madama Butterfly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f3740b707a806402fd725", "question": "What is often referred to as \"the powerhouse of the cell\"?", "answer": "The Mitochondrion, or mitochondria (plural)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1f", "question": "What is the capital of Poland?", "answer": "Warsaw", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904c", "question": "Who wrote the 1952 novel \"Giant\"?", "answer": "Edna Ferber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae9e", "question": "What did the 1944 education act raise the school leaving age to in the UK?", "answer": "15", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071c8a3745b36be73039cd", "question": "What is the name of the first space launch facility?", "answer": "Baikonur Cosmodrome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f8befa5fdd6dd25324f1", "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9bbba364247bf200fb8a6", "question": "What is the capital of Zambia?", "answer": "Lusaka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ec7260957c9fcac0ce71981", "question": "Who played Jason Mendoza in the popular TV series, \"The Good Place\"?", "answer": "Manny Jacinto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca73", "question": "A fathom is how many feet?", "answer": "6", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5b", "question": "In what novel would you find the character known as the Artful Dodger?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca64", "question": "What type of creature is an Orb Weaver?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13f", "question": "\"Safety Dance\" was a hit for which band?", "answer": "Men Without Hats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc2f4ec223966ae8f8879", "question": "Which major sports league does not let its players to wear the number 0?", "answer": "MLS", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b2", "question": "Who wrote the 1924 novel \"Beau Geste\"?", "answer": "P. C. Wren", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cfb0877e98cb97778a51", "question": "What does Machu Picchu translate to in English?", "answer": "Old mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d9", "question": "Facebook was first limited to students at what university?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b11be662d71a53650fce", "question": "What is the name of the giant flame creature the Fellowship faced in the Chamber of Mazarbul?", "answer": "Balrog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f2", "question": "What sport in the Olympics includes tucks, twists and pikes?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e95237ccba3ffe45786dc", "question": "Who sang the theme song for the TV show \"The Love Boat\"?", "answer": "Jack Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e8b5b24f84e0b9f9ffc6", "question": "What does the name Botswana mean?", "answer": "Land of the Tswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f91", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Turning Point\"?", "answer": "Leslie Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eadf8f83302ff91e46482", "question": "Who had hits with the songs \"Sledgehammer\"  and \"Big Time\" in the 1980s?", "answer": "Peter Gabriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa40", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72cf19d0874f1a5e2d1c29", "question": "How much liquid can be placed in a 10 gallon hat?", "answer": "3/4 of a gallon (US)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec7", "question": "Which British Sailor and Explorer was killed by Hawaiian natives in 1779?", "answer": "James Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab1b2f84fda37788a9a1dbf", "question": "Who is Tasmania named after?", "answer": "Abel Tasman", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d5", "question": "How many yards are there in a chain?", "answer": "22", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c88e6db22f44c2d77a29c43", "question": "Qeru Chay is a village in which country?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c285", "question": "What color does litmus paper turn if a solution is acidic?", "answer": "Pink or red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c5", "question": "Is it true that there is more vitamin C in a sweet red pepper than in a Valencia orange?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f16b40f7c52aae91cc07e5", "question": "What is the name of the apartment complex the Jetsons live in?", "answer": "Skypad Apartments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66a08a5bfecdd737e087f", "question": "What was the first company to air a legal TV commercial?", "answer": "Bulova watch company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a308", "question": "Which character did Madeleine Martin play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Becca Moody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc81aec223966ae8f888e", "question": "What is the name of the spider that paralyzes Frodo in the film \"The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King\"?", "answer": "Shelob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e2", "question": "What year did Andre and Edouard Michelin first publish the \"Michelin Guide\"?", "answer": "1900", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59da1c04f6756c9b30ba1500", "question": "Who was the star of the TV cooking show \"The Galloping Gourmet\"?", "answer": "Graham Kerr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99acb21a8909e5c332d23", "question": "The Kelvin scale is used to measure what?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6e", "question": "What parade first wound through New Orleans streets in 1838?", "answer": "Mardi Gras Parade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ef", "question": "Kat Dennings and Beth Behrs play the lead roles in what CBS TV show?", "answer": "Two Broke Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6a", "question": "What prospector is cremated in poet Robert Service's most famous ballad?", "answer": "Sam McGee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59675f432b59efe0e9417e99", "question": "What animal can dig a tunnel 300 feet long in just one night?", "answer": "A mole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399dc", "question": "On what TV show did Nell Carter work as a housekeeper for the Kanisky family?", "answer": "Gimme a Break!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e955a7ccba3ffe45786df", "question": "Malagasy is the native language of which African country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a728c336bcd28c119383282", "question": "What is the name of Christopher Lee's autobiography?", "answer": "Tall, Dark and Gruesome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca8", "question": "What country's liberation was the purpose of the 1991 Gulf War?", "answer": "Kuwait's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddc886ce05a3942286d9d", "question": "What is the name of the spaceship the crew of astronauts uses in the film \"Interstellar\"?", "answer": "The Endurance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c2", "question": "According to popular wisdom, you should only eat oysters in months whose names contain which letter?", "answer": "R", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07c", "question": "What WWII general was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc33a6ce05a3942286f20", "question": "In the film \"Capote\", who played the role of Truman Capote's love interest?", "answer": "Bruce Greenwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59524772736d4be723796b72", "question": "Approximately 7.5 million of what can be created from a cord of wood?", "answer": "Toothpicks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4dd5d06d333868d34d701", "question": "In which concentration camp did Anne Frank die?", "answer": "Bergen-Belsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16a6bf7c52aae91cc07dc", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", who is Alonso's son?", "answer": "Ferdinand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a18", "question": "What Italian town takes tourists to the workshop of renowned stringent-instrument maker Antonio Stradivari?", "answer": "Cremona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e448fe83fe1f2a824bb0", "question": "What was the location of the second major Allied assault into Europe in 1944?", "answer": "The attack of the French Mediterranean coast", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62a", "question": "What is the name of a small object orbiting the sun made of ice, dust and frozen gas?", "answer": "Comet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049ca6cf93664eb10486a9", "question": "Which famous rapper died on Friday, September 13, 1996?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f64", "question": "Whose halftime set at Super Bowl XLI was performed during a downpour?", "answer": "Prince's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a270", "question": "Who was the female lead in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Jane Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe937d26bd93ce3a4e5f678", "question": "Glossophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Public speaking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b732", "question": "Cherries jubilee was created and named in honor of what?", "answer": "Victoria's 75th year as queen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078197bd51d85e222ab64d", "question": "In 1908, what American artist painted elaborate murals in the newly completed Pennsylvania State Capitol Building?", "answer": "Edwin Austin Abbey\u00a0began an ambitious program of murals and other artworks for the newly completed Pennsylvania State Capitol.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f16a39f7c52aae91cc07d9", "question": "Who is the main character is Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Prospero", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1f", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Laurence Olivier and Gregory Peck?", "answer": "Douglas MacArthur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7fd", "question": "What are the four \"C\" used to evaluate the value and quality of a diamond?", "answer": "Carat, cut, clarity and color", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906d", "question": "In which of Charles Dickens' novels would you find the character Dora Spenlow?", "answer": "David Copperfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4e", "question": "In the novel \"To Kill a Mockingbird\", what was Atticus Finch's occupation?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b442", "question": "Where were the 1960 Winter Olympics held?", "answer": "Squaw Valley, California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb22", "question": "How many teaspoons are in a tablespoon?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd4747e83c707845b215c", "question": "What is Forrest Gump's IQ?", "answer": "75", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fc96a4edfd43a087adc0", "question": "Sweet Baby Broccoli is another name for what vegetable?", "answer": "Broccolini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339799", "question": "Glen Frey and Don Henley were members of which band?", "answer": "Eagles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ce683f302c3cfae5c79b719", "question": "On the day George Washington was first inaugurated as President of the United States, how many United States were there?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c122", "question": "What does the prefix \"pseudo\" mean?", "answer": "False", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21a", "question": "What Labrador retriever supplanted Socks the cat as the Clintons' favorite pet in 1997?", "answer": "Buddy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071e773745b36be73039e3", "question": "What year saw the release of issue #1 of the \"Revival\" comic book series?", "answer": "2012", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a090", "question": "What was John Wayne's real name?", "answer": "Marion Morrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76894eec85e375820b2a2", "question": "Which two U.S. national parks are located within the Arctic Circle?", "answer": "Gates of the Arctic National Park and Kobuk Valley National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339631", "question": "What city was the setting for the 1994 movie \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940f", "question": "What was the maiden name of \"Leave It to Beaver\" TV mom June Cleaver?", "answer": "Bronson", "category": "entertainment"}]